A. Daniel Delgado

adelgado1313@gmail.com +49 (172) 868-3535 elros.com.br

PROFILE

I'm a passionate craftsman with a keen eye for systems and 15+ years of experience in a broad range of technologies and industries. Throughout my career, I've become deeply versed in full-stack software development. What began as a focus on programming transitioned into a broader understanding that building software is as much about teamwork and collaboration as it is about technical skills.

Over the years, I've learned the importance of supporting and mentoring my team, ensuring we're not just producing output, but creating meaningful solutions. I enjoy enabling teams and individuals to sustainably deliver excellent products. The real value, I believe, is in building the right thing, and I'm committed to practices that prioritize that goal.

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

- English, French, Portuguese (Fluent)
- German, Spanish (Conversational)
- Mandarin Chinese (Beginner)

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

- Attended PUC-Rio for two years studying for a Bachelor of Computer Science.
- $\bullet \qquad \text{Held performance-based academic scholarship.} \\$

Professional Experience

Solutions Architect at Codelitt

October 2022 – June 2023

Brazil & Mexico

- Served as the technical expert during sales meetings with prospects and customers.
- Assisted in defining project scope, estimating resources, and assessing effort.
- Reviewed customer architectures to optimize delivery outcomes.
- Developed and collaborated on presentation materials for sales meetings.
- Partnered with external entities to maximize value for shared customers.
- Engaged in daily sales alignment for funnel performance and deal updates.
- Studied the Command of the Message technique.
- Studied the MEDDPICC methodology.

August 2021 – February 2022

Taiwan & Hungary

Engineering Manager at Learnerbly

- Transitioned from tech lead to overseeing team actions.
- Collaborated with multiple departments for strategic and technical planning.
- Curated processes and workflows to optimize project delivery.
- Promoted a high-trust environment through a self-organizing team model.
- Mentored individual team members on self-development and career progression.

Technical Lead at Learnerbly

October 2020 – August 2021

Taiwan

- Oversaw the consumer-facing platform and ran 121s with its team.
- Reviewed and improved workflows; facilitated team rituals and feedback.
- Organized technical discussions to enhance knowledge sharing.
- Focused on improving developer experience by automating tasks and refining CI.
- Led refactoring and migrations; reviewed code extensively.
- Played a leading role in designing and developing complex features.

Key technologies: TypeScript, JavaScript, Node, React, AWS, CSS, Styled Components GraphQL.

Software Developer at Moonfare

Germany

- Led a team responsible for implementing core financial services related to capital calls in F#.
- Collaborated closely with the financial team on domain logic.
- Implemented a tracking system using React and Node.js.
- Championed the shift from JavaScript to TypeScript.

Key technologies: Unix, AWS, TypeScript, Node, React, F#, GraphQL.

Head of Frontend Development at ArtFacts

September 2017 – September 2018

Germany

- Assisted this art world data broker during a complex product launch, addressing customer frustrations due to bugs and missing features in the product.
- · Improved development by introducing modern practices: code reviews, automated testing, CI, and linting.
- · Mentored a junior developer on tooling, technologies, and system abstractions, leading to increased productivity.
- · Collaborated with the CEO and CFO to align on overall business goals and manage shifting priorities.
- · Participated in discussions for refining the business model and finding a tighter product-market fit.
- Balanced short-term commitments with long-term business objectives by negotiating reduced product scopes, prioritize work items efficiently, and manage technical debt.

Key technologies: Unix, TypeScript, React, Redux, Mocha.

Software Developer at Creators Media

July 2013 – March 2017

Germany & USA

- Implemented features based on diverse departmental requests, developed according to mock-ups and specs.
- Created an authoring tool for staff writers and the public, incorporating third-party content integration in the
 tool and providing support for polls, quizzes, proofreading, and editorial features.
- Managed a remote developer for customizations on an open-source chat system.
- · Developed a cross-property internal SDK facilitating analytics, tracking, and authentication functionalities.

<u>Key technologies:</u> Unix, ECMAScript, CoffeeScript, React, Redux, Node, Express, Backbone, Mocha, Ruby, Rails, Jade, Sass, Stylus, MySQL.

Software Developer at WeGreen

February 2013 - June 2013

Brazil & Germany

- Developed features for mobile and desktop versions of a sustainable products marketplace.
- Packaged the main website as a native iOS app.

Key technologies: Unix, JavaScript, Knockout, PHP, Symfony, Cordova/PhoneGap.

Software Developer at Pontomobi

June 2012 — December 2012

Brazil

- Developed an in-house ad server and supported legacy systems.
- Implemented new features for legacy ad-server client libraries on iOS and Android.

 $\underline{Key\ technologies:}\ Unix, JavaScript, Node, Express, Angular, PHP, Android, Java, iOS, Objective-C.$

Software Developer at Braspag / MundiPagg

 $August\ 2010-May\ 2012$

Brazil

- Participated in the development of a new transactional (payment processing) platform.
- Developed modules for credit card acquirer integration and customer APIs.
- Joined the founding team of MundiPagg for their first transactional platform.

Key technologies: Windows, C#, .NET, SOA, SOAP, REST, PHP.

Software Developer at Fábrica Digital

 $March\ 2008-February\ 2009$

Brazil

- Translated wireframes and mockups into styles and markup.
- Developed custom components for CMS systems and developed web applications.

Key technologies: Unix, Lua, Kepler, Publique!, PHP, Drupal, CSS, HTML.